

Miguel Solans

V.N. Famalicão/Portugal | +351 965 674 513 cmiguelsolans@gmail.com

github | in linkedin

SUMMARY

I am very passionate about technology in general and my path towards Software Development world has began in High-School, on a Professional Course of Electronics, Automation and Computers. Right after, I took a Computer Engineer BSc Degree at the Polytechnic Institute of Cávado and Ave, followed by a MSc with specialisation studies under Software Development and Distributed Systems - I also took Software Testing and Web Development as complementary studies.

Despite my love for the Web, I am currently working as a iOS Developer and writing thesis on this subject.

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

POLYTECHNIC INSTITUTE OF CÁVADO AND AVE

2016 - 2019

BSC IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING

- Maths
- Algorithms and Data Structures
- Software Development
- Project Management
- Networks and Operating Systems

UNIVERSITY OF MINHO 2019 - Present

MSc in Computer Engineering

- Specialization on Distributed Systems and Software Development & Project Management;
- Complementary Studies on Web Development and Software Testing

EXPERIENCE

WEDO TECHNOLOGIES

February 2019 until July 2019

INTERN AS WEB DEVELOPER

• Incorporating new Data Visualization Components on RAID Web based Application

ITSECTOR October 2020 until April 2021

INTERN AS IOS DEVELOPER

• Integration of Multi-Factor Hardware Based Authentication System for Online Bank Transactions

ITSECTOR April 2021 until today

FULL-TIME IOS DEVELOPER

SKILLS ___

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES Experienced: Objective-C | JavaScript Familiar: Swift | Java | C#

SOFTWARE AND TOOLS Xcode | NodeJS | WebStorm | Git | Terminal

DATABASE SYSTEMS MySQL | MongoDB

FRAMEWORKS & LIBRARIES AFNetworking | Alamofire | ExpressJS | Mongoose | VueJS

CERTIFICATIONS _

- · Android Training Program Portugal. By Google. Issued on March 2019.
- iOS Sector Academy. By ITSector. Issued on October 2020.

NONPROFIT PROJECTS

- Manager and Web Developer for Mentour Pilot, from May 2016 until December 2018. https://mentourpilot.com
- ISN Informatics Social Network. https://github.com/miguelsolans/UMINHO-ISN
- · Mantis An Equivalence system for University of Minho. https://github.com/miguelsolans/Mantis
- BookyMe A Generalist Booking Platform. https://github.com/miguelsolans/BookyMe